{
    "id": "fa3b353c12f14104914ee18dc6f80ce4",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It was such a comic state of affairs ……………………….. we had to laugh.",
            "description": "The correlative conjunction used in this structure is such...that.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "that",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The negotiations collapsed …………………………. no agreement could be reached.",
            "description": "All of the above can be used here with slightly different meanings.",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "when",
                "since",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "I like you better …………………………… I like him.",
            "description": "In comparative expressions we use than.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "then",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will need the car …………………………….. you will have to hire a taxi.",
            "description": "We cannot use then to connect two ideas spoken by the same speaker.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "then",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "‘I will be busy in the morning’. ‘………………………. I will come in the afternoon.’",
            "description": "Then is used when one speaker replies to another.",
            "answers": [
                "So",
                "Then",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Many things have happened ………………………….. we last met.",
            "description": "Since can indicate time. It is mainly used with perfect tenses. ",
            "answers": [
                "from",
                "since",
                "when"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Janet can sing beautifully and …………………………… can her sister.",
            "description": "This structure with so is used to add to the sentence before.",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "so",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I scored good marks, …………………………….. I had not prepared for the exam.",
            "description": "Even though has a past reference. It is an emphatic form of though and although.",
            "answers": [
                "even though",
                "even if",
                "even"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She says that she will come …………………………….. there is a bus strike next week.",
            "description": "Even if has a future reference.",
            "answers": [
                "even if",
                "even though",
                "even"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Grievances cannot be addressed …………………………………. they are spoken about.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "unless",
                "without"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She would rather dance ………………………… sing.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "to",
                "then"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}